CHRIS EMERFOLL

Full-Stack Software Developer

GitHub: https://github.com/Emerfoll@gmail.com/Emerfoll@gmail.com

Phone: (763) - 225 - 7536

----- Summary ------

Dedicated developer with extensive background in various coding languages, building mobile responsive sites, and developing full-stack web applications from the ground up. Strong desire for understanding and continuous learning in this fast-paced industry. Professional strengths include problem-solving, fast learner, written and verbal communication, and time management. Detail-oriented mindset from 3+ years in the computer industry.

----- Technical Skills -----

Languages: JavaScript | HTML | CSS

Libraries and Frameworks : React.js | React Native | Node.js | Express.js | jQuery |

Redux | Redux-Saga | Bootstrap | Material-UI

Databases : PostgreSQL

Version Control : Git | GitHub

Software: Visual Studio Code | Postico | Postman | npm | API | Homebrew | Mac OSX |

Windows 10

---- Experience -----

Prime Digital Academy - Full Stack Web Development Student:

October 2020 - March 2021

- Solo Project: <u>Beer Book</u>
 - Created a full-stack web application for users (beer lovers) to find, add, and track different kinds of beers they have tried and whether or not they enjoyed them.
 - Technologies used: PostgreSQL, Express.js, ReactJS, Node.js, Passport.js, Redux, Redux-Saga, CSS, Material-UI, Heroku
- Group Project: SnowSwaps
 - Created a mobile-friendly online marketplace for members of snow-loving communities to buy, sell, or browse used snow-sport equipment.
 - Technologies used: PostgreSQL, Express.js, ReactJS, Node.js, NodeMailer.js, Passport.js, Redux, Redux-Saga, CSS, Material-UI, Heroku
- Projects: You can find a list of current projects and projects I have worked on during, and after my training at Prime on GitHub: https://github.com/Emerfoll

Ehome LLC - Senior Computer Technician:

April 2017 - November 2020

- Collaborated with other Senior Technicians to resolve workflow issues, production speed, and traceability on units processed.
- Designed a program to track and examine the quality of all repairs performed by Apple or other "out-of-house" companies.
- Performed more complicated hardware repairs on computers. Replaced components on computers like screens, LogicBoards, ports, and other non-user replaceable parts.
- Interfaced with a diverse customer base multiple times daily to find the right products and resolve issues.

Cummins Power Generation - Assembly:

August 2016 - March 2017

- Assembled machinery in a collaborative and fast paced work environment while maintaining a clean and organized workstation and safe work practices.
- Operated cranes, hoists, and other heavy machinery.
- Built generator engines, carburetors, oil pans, etc.

Nortech - Machine Operator:

April 2015 - July 2016

- Examined PC boards for any defects, faulty components, insufficient soldering, and blueprint discrepancies.
- Set-up, programmed, and operated "pick and place" SMT machines.
- Directed inspection and support staff for any machine issues and machine changeovers.

Boston Scientific - Machine Operator:

August 2013 - February 2015

- Operated silicone injection molding and various other machines for medical devices.
- Directed other operators on when a model change over would occur.
- Examined medical device parts and products for any flaws or imperfections.
- Logged and tracked information into computer software for traceability.

Education	

Prime Digital Academy - Full Stack Software Engineering Certification:

Completed - March 2021